Dr. Po-Hsun Tseng

6+ years experience of large-scale software development with C programming on the Linux system throughout my Ph.D. journey.

Seeking a challenging and rewarding opportunity with low-level system programming (eg. device driver, Linux kernel, CPU architecture) to apply my skills at a fabless company.



CONTACT

zengbs@gmail.com

+886 966 587 832

Hsinchu, Taiwan

https://github.com/zengbs

SKILLS

Programming

C Bash scripting System programming CUDA Python

Operating System

Linux - user
Linux - kernel

Architecture

ARM architecture

Software & Tools

Git
Vim
Gdb
Valgrind

Languages

Chinese (native)

English - writing

English - speaking

English - listening

English - reading

EDUCATION

6 08/2016 - 06/2022

National Taiwan University, Taiwan

Ph.D. in Computational Physics

- Developed and implemented a new algorithm to reduce numerical error by 10^6 compared to conventional one. See Fig. 16 in (https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.11130).
- Designed a new approach to further promote the robustness of GAMMER. The new approach was adopted in the research project led by Dr. Kuo-Chuan Pan from Tsing Hua University.

 See the merged branch: (https://github.com/gamer-project/gamer/pull/60/files)
- Worked on improving the GAMER collaborated with Dr. Tzihong Chiueh and Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive. See the Section *References*.
- A main contributor of the gammer-project on GitHub.

 See: (https://github.com/gamer-project/gamer/graphs/contributors)
- Built NIS, NFS, and Linux cluster from scratch with colleagues and worked with Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive to bootstrap simulations for research.

WORK HISTORY

12/2014 - 01/2016

TDK corporation, Singapore Circuit designer

Design the circiut of surface acoustic wave(SAW) filters

6 08/2013 - 08/2014

Military Service

EDUCATION

09/2011 - 07/2013

National Taiwan University, Taiwan

M.Sc. in Physics

1 09/2006 - 07/2011

♀ National Central University, Taiwan

B.Sc. in Mathematics

SOFT SKILLS

 Nonverbal communication
 Active listening
 Open mindedness

 Patience
 Mutual respect
 Teamwork
 Brainstorming

 Collaboration

GENERAL SKILLS

Numerical algorithm Large-scale project cscope makefile

GNU autotools

PUBLICATIONS

An adaptive mesh, GPU-accelerated, and error minimized special relativistic hydrodynamics code

Po-Hsun Tseng, Hsi-Yu Schive, Tzihong Chiueh

Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society Vol. 504, pp. 3298-3315
https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.11130

The symmetry problem of the Fermi and eROSITA bubbles: A proof-of-concept study
Po-Hsun Tseng, Hsiang-Yi Karen Yang, Hsi-Yu Schive, Chun-Yen Chen, Tzihong Chiueh

2022 preprint

TALKS

• An adaptive-mesh, GPU-accelerated, and optimally error-controlled special relativistic hydrodynamics code Oral (remote), American Center for Physics College Park, U.S.A

Mar. 2021

A new and accurate code for simulating special relativistic hydrodynamics
 Oral, Annual Meeting of the Physical Society of Taiwan, NPTU.

Feb. 2020

REFERENCES

- Please send an appointment letter to request a call. 😃
- Dr. Tzihong Chiueh

Distinguished Professor, Institute of Astrophysics, National Taiwan University

- ▼ Taipei 10617, Taiwan
- chiuehth@phys.ntu.edu.tw
- +886 2 3366 8628
- Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive

Assistant Professor, Institute of Astrophysics, National Taiwan University

- ▼ Taipei 10617, Taiwan
- hyschive@phys.ntu.edu.tw
- **** +886 2 3366 8644
- Dr. Hsiang-Yi Karen Yang

Assistant Professor, Institute of Astronomy, National Tsing Hua University

- Hsinchu 30013, Taiwan
- hyang@phys.nthu.edu.tw
- **4886** 3 574 2953